<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tags on Miguel Magalhães</title>
    <link>https://magamig.github.io/tags/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tags on Miguel Magalhães</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://magamig.github.io/tags/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking @ The Real Python Podcast</title>
      <link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/talking-the-real-python-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/talking-the-real-python-podcast/</guid>
      <description>This week, I was a guest at the The Real Python Podcast - a weekly Python podcast hosted by Christopher Bailey. It includes interviews, coding tips, and conversation with guests from the Python community.
As co-organizers of DjangoCon Europe 2021, David and I talked a bit about the conference: how the organization of the virtual event has been, some of the difficulties in the process (it was supposed to be a physical conference at Porto), and what makes it different and exciting!</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time Video Convolution using WebGL</title>
      <link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/real-time-video-convolution-using-webgl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/real-time-video-convolution-using-webgl/</guid>
      <description>A convolution is a mathematical operation that is done by multiplying a pixel’s and its neighboring pixels color value by a weighted matrix, and then adding those values together (for all the pixels of an image). The small matrix that defines the weights of the multiplication is named kernel or convolution matrix. This is used to apply effects to an image such as blurring, sharpening, outlining, and more (defined throught a kernel).</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Inner Workings</title>
      <link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/the-inner-workings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/the-inner-workings/</guid>
      <description>If creating your personal page has been on your mind for a while, I hope this blog post inspires you to go through with it. This is not intended to be a manual, but an overview of my own process.
As I&amp;rsquo;ve previously mentioned, it is important to define some guidelines of what we want to achieve (even if later on we need to change them). As such, this webpage is intended to be lightweight and fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World!</title>
      <link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the computer programming cliché phrase:
&amp;gt; Hello, World
It&amp;rsquo;s 2021 and I&amp;rsquo;m currently living in France as a grad student in a computer science program. &amp;ldquo;Inspired by the French writers Victor Hugo, Voltaire, and Gustave Flaubert, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start my blog!&amp;quot; - not really, but I admit it would be cooler. This will be the place to share my personal projects, ideas, and experiences.
Before starting any project, such as this blog, I think it is important to define what you want to achieve, your goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
