<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tags on Miguel Magalhães</title>
    <link>https://magamig.github.io/tags/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tags on Miguel Magalhães</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://magamig.github.io/tags/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing a Conference With More Than 400 Attendees</title>
      <link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/organizing-a-conference-with-more-than-400-attendees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/organizing-a-conference-with-more-than-400-attendees/</guid>
      <description>Last week, DjangoCon Europe 2021 took place completelly online from the 2nd to the 6th of June. The conference main focus is the web framework Django, it happens yearly in Europe, and it includes 5 days of talks, sprints, and tutorials. I was the lead co-organizer and it was completelly exhausting!
Orginally, the conference was planned to take place phisically at the Super Bock Arena in Porto, Portugal; we had to shift to a different approach and make a virtual conference (yet again).</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Scraping for a COVID-19 Vaccine</title>
      <link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/scraping-for-a-covid-19-vaccine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/scraping-for-a-covid-19-vaccine/</guid>
      <description>ℹ️ COVID-19 vaccine Learn more from the World Health Organization.
 Earlier today, I went to get my first COVID-19 vaccine dose. Although accross the pond it might seem normal for a young person to be getting the vaccine, it&amp;rsquo;s still considered early for continental Europe, in particular France. So how did I get mine?
Firstly, I&amp;rsquo;d like to make it clear that I did not cut in line! The elderly population, health care and other essential workers, or those clinically vulnurable are already vaccinated by now (or have access to a priority queue).</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking @ The Real Python Podcast</title>
      <link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/talking-the-real-python-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/talking-the-real-python-podcast/</guid>
      <description>This week (at the time of writing), I was a guest at the The Real Python Podcast - a weekly Python podcast hosted by Christopher Bailey. It includes interviews, coding tips, and conversation with guests from the Python community.
As co-organizers of DjangoCon Europe 2021, David and I talked a bit about the conference: how the organization of the virtual event has been, some of the difficulties in the process (it was supposed to be a physical conference at Porto), and what makes it different and exciting!</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time Video Convolution Using WebGL</title>
      <link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/real-time-video-convolution-using-webgl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/real-time-video-convolution-using-webgl/</guid>
      <description>A convolution is a mathematical operation that is done by multiplying a pixel’s and its neighboring pixels color value by a weighted matrix, and then adding those values together (for all the pixels of an image). The small matrix that defines the weights of the multiplication is called kernel or convolution matrix. This is used to apply effects to an image such as blurring, sharpening, outlining, and more; where each effect uses a distinct kernel.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Inner Workings</title>
      <link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/the-inner-workings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/the-inner-workings/</guid>
      <description>If creating your personal page has been on your mind for a while, I hope this blog post inspires you to go through with it. This is not intended to be a manual, but an overview of my own process.
As I&amp;rsquo;ve previously mentioned, it is important to define some guidelines of what we want to achieve (even if later on we need to change them). As such, this webpage is intended to be lightweight and fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World!</title>
      <link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the computer programming cliché phrase:
&amp;gt; Hello, World
It&amp;rsquo;s 2021 and I&amp;rsquo;m currently living in France as a grad student in a computer science program. &amp;ldquo;Inspired by the French writers Victor Hugo, Voltaire, and Gustave Flaubert, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start my blog!&amp;quot; - not really, but I admit it would be cooler. This will be the place to share my personal projects, ideas, and experiences.
Before starting any project, such as this blog, I think it is important to define what you want to achieve, your goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    
    
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
