<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Miguel Magalhães</title><link>https://magamig.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Miguel Magalhães</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 18:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://magamig.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2022 in Retrospective</title><link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/2022-in-retrospective/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 18:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/2022-in-retrospective/</guid><description>My last year was both challenging and rewarding, with a lot happening in such a short period of time. Although, I haven&amp;rsquo;t been as active here as I wanted to (due to everything else I had to attend), I am writing this post to do a retrospective of 2022. Besides being able to share this with you, the writing of this blog post should help me look back at this period of my life to consider what went well (or not) but also what I have learned during this period.</description></item><item><title>Accurate Image Alignment and Registration using OpenCV</title><link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/accurate-image-alignment-and-registration-using-opencv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/accurate-image-alignment-and-registration-using-opencv/</guid><description>The image alignment and registration pipeline takes two input images that contain the same scene from slightly different viewing angles. The picture above displays both input images side by side with the common scene (object) being the painting Las Meninas (1656) by Velázquez, currently at the Museo del Prado in Madrid (Spain).
The first step is computing the projection that establishes the mathematical relationships which maps pixel coordinates from one image to another 1.</description></item><item><title>Modding a Xiaomi M365 Electric Scooter</title><link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/modding-a-xiaomi-m365-electric-scooter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/modding-a-xiaomi-m365-electric-scooter/</guid><description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been riding my Xiaomi M365 quite a lot during this summer in sunny Portugal. However, since I&amp;rsquo;m 1.93m and weight over 90kg, the electric scooter has some issues on handling steep inclines (specially on cobblestone, which is extremely common over here).
To improve the riding experience, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to mod the scooter. When doing this, one must take into account the balance between the extra power and the motor/battery wear.</description></item><item><title>Crossing an Entire Country in a Straight Line</title><link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/crossing-an-entire-country-in-a-straight-line/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/crossing-an-entire-country-in-a-straight-line/</guid><description>Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve crossed an entire country in a straight line. &amp;ldquo;Why?&amp;quot;, you might ask&amp;hellip; why not? Inspired by Tom Davies (aka GeoWizard), I decided to go on this harmless challenge across&amp;hellip; Monaco! Not as exciting as Tom&amp;rsquo;s missions across Norway or Wales, but good enough as an adventure.
Before embarking on this trip, some planning had to be done. Since Monaco is a small country, we had to cross a small distance.</description></item><item><title>Organizing a Conference with More Than 400 Participants</title><link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/organizing-a-conference-with-more-than-400-participants/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/organizing-a-conference-with-more-than-400-participants/</guid><description>Last week, DjangoCon Europe 2021 took place completelly online from the 2nd to the 6th of June. This yearly european conference focuses on the web framework Django, and it includes 5 days of talks, sprints, and tutorials. I was the lead co-organizer and it was both extremelly fullfilling and completelly exhausting!
Orginally, the conference was planned to take place physically at the Super Bock Arena in Porto, Portugal; we had to shift to a different approach and make the conference virtual (yet again).</description></item><item><title>Scraping for a COVID-19 Vaccine</title><link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/scraping-for-a-covid-19-vaccine/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/scraping-for-a-covid-19-vaccine/</guid><description>ℹ️ COVID-19 vaccine Learn more from the World Health Organization.
Earlier today, I went to get my first COVID-19 vaccine dose. Although accross the pond it might seem normal for a young person to be getting the vaccine, it&amp;rsquo;s still considered early for continental Europe, in particular France. So how did I get mine?
Firstly, I&amp;rsquo;d like to make it clear that I did not cut in line! The elderly population, health care and other essential workers, or those clinically vulnurable are already vaccinated by now (or have access to a priority queue).</description></item><item><title>Talking @ The Real Python Podcast</title><link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/talking-the-real-python-podcast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/talking-the-real-python-podcast/</guid><description>This week (at the time of writing), I was a guest at the The Real Python Podcast - a weekly Python podcast hosted by Christopher Bailey. It includes interviews, coding tips, and conversation with guests from the Python community.
As co-organizers of DjangoCon Europe 2021, David and I talked a bit about the conference: how the organization of the virtual event has been, some of the difficulties in the process (it was supposed to be a physical conference at Porto), and what makes it different and exciting!</description></item><item><title>Real-Time Video Convolution Using WebGL</title><link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/real-time-video-convolution-using-webgl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/real-time-video-convolution-using-webgl/</guid><description>A convolution is a mathematical operation that is done by multiplying a pixel’s and its neighboring pixels color value by a weighted matrix, and then adding those values together (for all the pixels of an image). The small matrix that defines the weights of the multiplication is called kernel or convolution matrix. This is used to apply effects to an image such as blurring, sharpening, outlining, and more; where each effect uses a distinct kernel.</description></item><item><title>The Inner Workings</title><link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/the-inner-workings/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Mar 2021 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/the-inner-workings/</guid><description>If creating your personal page has been on your mind for a while, I hope this blog post inspires you to go through with it. This is not intended to be a manual, but an overview of my own process.
As I&amp;rsquo;ve previously mentioned, it is important to define some guidelines of what we want to achieve (even if later on we need to change them). As such, this webpage is intended to be lightweight and fast.</description></item><item><title>Hello, World!</title><link>https://magamig.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 21:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://magamig.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the computer programming cliché phrase:
&amp;gt; Hello, World
It&amp;rsquo;s 2021 and I&amp;rsquo;m currently living in France as a grad student in a computer science program. &amp;ldquo;Inspired by the French writers Victor Hugo, Voltaire, and Gustave Flaubert, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start my blog!&amp;quot; - not really, but I admit it would be cooler. This will be the place to share my personal projects, ideas, and experiences.
Before starting any project, such as this blog, I think it is important to define what you want to achieve, your goals.</description></item></channel></rss>